astd.org 2001-06-03

# E Learning Community

|   |    
ASTD Web Site Privacy Statement 

ASTD respects the privacy of its members and visitors to the ASTD Web site. ASTD **_does not_** collect any information through the Web site without the knowledge of the member or visitor. ASTD's Web server automatically recognizes only the visitor's domain name, not the specific user name of the visitor. ASTD does not collect any information via cookies or other tracking means of a personal nature from visitors. All personal information collected through the Web site is provided on a voluntary basis by ASTD Web site visitors through a visible means of data entry or collection. 

One of the main objectives of ASTD's Web site, however, is to encourage networking and participation in interactive events by ASTD members and site visitors. To support this networking and interaction, ASTD may require that visitors provide information to access certain areas of its Web site. This information may include name, email and postal addresses, phone numbers, and other demographic information. Areas of our Web site requiring this information generally include any interactive area, such as forum and chat discussions, surveys, on-site registrations and applications, and future features such as a national job bank and email notification services. Visitors provide this information on a voluntary basis to gain access to these areas. ASTD may also collect aggregate information on which pages visitors access as they use our site as well as the email addresses with visitors who correspond with us directly from the Web site. 

Information about members collected through the Membership Application will be stored in the general ASTD membership database. ASTD may use email or postal addresses for notifying members and customers about upcoming online events, new additions to the ASTD Web site, or other products and services offered by ASTD. Member contact information is also made available through the ASTD Membership Directory, a searchable database of members on ASTD's Web site made available only to national members of ASTD. If you are a member of ASTD and do not wish to be included in the database, please send an email to [info@astd.org](mailto:info@astd.org) indicating that you do not want to be in the Membership Directory. 

ASTD does make our membership and conference attendee list available to other reputable organizations whose products or services we think you might find interesting. If you do not want to receive any mail (electronic or otherwise) from any organization to which ASTD sells its membership mailing list, please let us know by emailing us at [info@astd.org](mailto:info@astd.org). 

ASTD does not provide any of the email addresses, postal addresses, phone numbers, or other personally identifiable information that it collects on its Web site (except for through the interactive membership application) to any other individual or organization for any purpose, including commercial. ASTD uses the information we collect to improve the content of our Web site; to enhance existing products, services, and member benefits; and to plan for new products, services, and member benefits. 

If you provide your telephone or fax number on the Web site, ASTD may contact you via telephone regarding any questions they may have about a product or service order (including membership applications, conference registrations, or other product orders). Therefore, it is important that you provide us with your correct phone number to serve you more promptly. If you do not wish to receive further phone calls from ASTD, please contact [info@astd.org](mailto:info@astd.org). 

ASTD will use the aggregate data we collect to perform statistical analysis of the collective characteristics and behavior of our members and visitors, to measure overall customer demographics, and to analyze how and where to use our resources. We may also use the aggregate data collected to inform our advertisers and sponsors with an aggregate customer profile of who is visiting the Web site, and the number of customers who have seen and "clicked" on their advertisements. 

In our chat rooms and threaded discussions, we do collect all logins and dialogue. Dialogue in scheduled chat sessions may be archived for later retrieval by any ASTD Web site visitor. Personal information, personal references, and obvious grammatical errors will be removed from the chat transcripts before they are archived. Otherwise, ASTD does not edit any dialogue provided through chat or threaded discussion participation. 

ASTD, however, cannot control the acts of its members or visitors who use the chat feature during unscheduled events. If personal information, such as name, email addresses, mailing addresses, and phone numbers, are provided through these modules, they may be used by other parties outside of ASTD for unsolicited e-mail or other contact. 

If you feel that ASTD has violated this Privacy Statement in any way, please contact us at [webmaster@astd.org](mailto:webmaster@astd.org) so that we may address the issue. 

**American Society for Training and Development (ASTD)**  
© Copyright 2000 | Disclaimer | Privacy Statement  
1640 King Street, Box 1443  
Alexandria, Virginia, 22313-2043, USA  
Phone: (703) 683-8100 - Fax: (703) 683-8103  
|
